Enumerate Function:
A lot of times when dealing with iterators, we also get a need to keep a count of iterations. Python eases the programmers’ task by providing a built-in function enumerate() for this task.
Enumerate() method adds a counter to an iterable and returns it in a form of enumerate object. This enumerate object can then be used directly in for loops or be converted into a list of tuples using list() method.
Syntax:
enumerate(iterable, start)
Parameter Values:
Parameter	Description
iterable	An iterable object
start	A Number. Defining the start number of the enumerate object. Default 0
Example:
>>>x = ('cse', 'mech', 'ece')
>>>y = enumerate(x)
>>>print(list(y))
[(0,’cse’),(1,’mech’),(2,’ece’)]

❮ Built-in Functions

